Legend tells of a legendary warrior...
传说中有一名传奇武林高手
...whose kung fu skills were the stuff of legend.
他的武划早已成为传说
He traveled the land in search of worthy foes.
他在江湖四外流浪，寻找对手
Il see you like to chew. Maybe you should chew on my fist!
你好像很党吃哦 你不如吃我一源吧
The warrior said nothing, for his mouth was full.
大使在吃东西，所以没回话
Then he swallowed. And then he spoke.
他终於春下食物，然后说…
Enough talk. Let's fight!
魔话少说、放马遇来 !
Shashabooey!
我条条条 !
He was so deadly in fact,
他的届气太重…
that his enemies would go blind from overexposure to pure awesomeness.
对手看到他的英交就会驳瞎
- My eyes! - He's too awesome!
我眼睛瞎了! 他太杀了 !
- And attractive. - How can we repay you?
而且超钙的! 我们该如何报签你?
There is no charge for awesomeness.
行侠仗义…不须回报
Or attractiveness.
长得证气也是…
It mattered not how many foes he faced.
不管他面对多少对手
They were no match for his bodacity!
对方都抵抽不了他的超凡武划
Never before had a panda been so feared! And so loved.
江湖上和从未出现这广角的驴猫 ! 而且人和气超旺!
Even the most heroic heroes in China,
就连中国最帮害的武林高手
the Furious Five,
蔓世五侠…
bowed in respect to this great master.
都对这名伟大侠士甘拜下风 !
We should hang out.
咱们麻该一起找乐子
Agreed.
同意
But hanging out would have to wait.
不明他们没时间找乐子
Because when you're facing the 10,000 demons of Demon Mountain,
因为一旦面对凶神恶笋
there's only one thing that matters and that's...
唯有一件事才是关键 那就是…
Po! Get up!
阿波 ! 起床 !
You'll be late for work!
快速到了 !
Po! Get up!
阿波 ! 给我起床 !
Po. What are you doing up there?
你在搞什么东束 ?
Nothing.
汽什么
Monkey! Mantis! Crane! Viper! Tigress!
猴王 ! 快星师 ! 震鹤 ! 俏小龙 ! 悍寻虎 !
Po! Let's go! You're late for work.
阿波 ! 快点 ! 上工了!
Coming!
我来了啦
Sorry, Dad.
对不起，老区
Sorry doesn't make the noodles.
对不起又不能当天吃
What were you doing up there? All that noise.
你在恤问搞什么鬼 ?
Nothing. I just had a crazy dream.
没有呀，只是做了一场葛
About what?
什么葛 ?
What were you dreaming about?
你做了什千样的薄 ?
What was I...?
我的萝?
l was dreaming about...
我葛到…
Noodles? You were really dreaming about noodles?
类人条 ? 你真的欧到类休 ?
Yeah. What else would I be dreaming about?
是啊，要不然吓 ?
Careful! That soup is sharp.
小心汤站上面的…乘色
Oh, happy day!
我好高愉哦
My son, finally having the noodle dream!
我儿子终从欧到类人条了 !
You don't know how long I've been waiting for this moment.
你不知道这一刻我等了多入
This is a sign, Po.
这是个好征兆，阿波 !
A sign of what?
什么微兆?
You are almost ready to be entrusted with the secret ingredient
你就快要可以继承…
Then you will fulfill your destiny and take over the restaurant!
然后你就能接掌这家类店
As I took it over from my father, who took it over from his father...
就像我从我老区那里接掌… 他从他老和葡那里接掌的类让
...who won it from a friend in mahjong.
只不遇这是他老匈 打麻将赢来的
Dad, Dad, Dad, it was just a dream.
老爸，那只是一场葛
No, it was the dream.
不，那是你的时生欧想
We are noodle folk. Broth runs through our veins.
类店老畔就连血都流著咎混
But, Dad, didn't you ever want to do something else?
老爸，你有想过做别的事吗 ?
Something besides noodles?
除了类人条以外…
Actually, when I was young and crazy,
事实上，当我年少地狂时
I thought about running away and learning how to make tofu.
我曾考虑逃跑去学做豆腐
Why didn't you?
那你怎广没这样做呢 ?
Because it was a stupid dream.
咀，那只是一个蚌夸的葛想
Can you imagine me making tofu?
你能想像我做豆腐的样子吗?
Tofu.
哈…做豆商…
No! We all have our place in this world.
不，每个人都有安身立足之处
Mine is here, and yours is...
我的是这壬 而你的是…
I know, is here.
我虹，这壬
No, it's at tables 2, 5, 7, and 12
不，选有外场 !
Service with a smile.
上菜时要微笑
Well done, students... if you were trying to disappoint me.
招式漂亮，徒弟 只可惜令人失望
Tigress, you need more ferocity! Monkey, greater speed.
悍寻虎，不久猛 猴王，速度太慢
Crane, height. Viper, subtlety. Mantis...
昨欧，屎不金高，俏小衣 不锡细心，快星晴…
- Master Shifu. - What?!
功夫大师 ! 干骂?
It's Master Oogway. He wants to see you.
是…竭大仙，他要昂你
Master Oogway, you summoned me? Is something wrong?
苑大仙，你找我 ? 发生什么事吗 ?
Why must something be wrong for me to want to see my old friend?
没事不能找你吗，老友?
So, nothing's wrong?
所以没事 ?
Well, didn't say that.
这个嘛…我没这样说
You were saying?
你刚刚说到…
I have had a vision.
我有预感
Tai Lung will return.
残豹会回来
That is impossible! He is in prison.
不可能，他被关在大牢
Nothing is impossible.
世上没有不可能的事
Zeng!
小张 !
Fly to Chorh-Gom prison and tell them
快民去长顺大补 !
to double the guards, double their weapons, double everything!
叫他们加倍守本人数 ! 加倍武装 ! 加倍所有防备 !
Tai Lung does not leave that prison!
千万不能让残豹逃出来 !
Yes, Master Shifu!
遵伟，功夫大师
One often meets his destiny on the road he takes to avoid it.
人求这把法逃避宿命
We must do something! We can't let him march on the valley, take his revenge!
我们必须想办法… 不能让他回来和平谷展开复优 !
He'll...
他会…他会…
Your mind is like this water, my friend.
你的思绪就像这水面，朋友
When it is agitated, it becomes difficult to see.
一旦起了溃注，就很难看清楚
But if you allow it to settle...
但只要平心静气
..the answer becomes clear.
一切就能照然若皆
The Dragon Scroll.
神龙秘笈
It is time.
是聘候了
But who? Who is worthy to be trusted with the secret to limitless power?
不过是谁呢 ? 谁值得旗付毯极神功秘读?
To become the Dragon Warrior?
有资格成为…神龙大侠呢 ?
I don't know.
我也不知道
Excuse me. Pardon me. Sorry.
借通，不好意思…
Watch it!
小心哑，阿波
Sorry. Suck it up!
元热，缩小腹 !
Sorry. A thousand pardons.
歹吉，有金歹势
What?
啥米?
Master Oogway's choosing the Dragon Warrior! Today!
欧大仙要挑出神龙大侠 就是今天 !
Everyone! Get to the Jade Palace! One of the Five is gonna get the Dragon Scroll!
大采儿 ! 大彩儿 ! 快，快去玉皇富 !
We've waited 1,000 years for this! Take the bowl!
我们已经等了一千年了! 把类带去吃吧 !
This is the greatest day in kung fu history! Just go!
这是武林最大休的事 不用小费啦，快点去
Po! Where are you going?
阿波 ! 你要去哪里?
To the Jade Palace.
去…玉皇宫
You're forgetting your noodle cart.
列总了带类人条推车
The whole valley will be there, and you'll sell noodles to all of them.
所有和平谷的居民都会去看 你可以这站大呈一笔
Selling noodles?
袁类 ?
But, Dad, I was thinking, maybe I...
可是老爷…我在想…或许我…
- Yeah? - l was thinking maybe I...
什么 ? 我在想或许我…
..could also sell the bean buns. They're about to go bad.
也能间豆沙包 包子…再不习就要过期了
That's my boy!
好样的
I told you that dream was a sign.
我就说那场欧是个好兆头
Yeah. Glad I had it.
是啊，哈哈，真是好欧 议啊 !
- I'm a kung fu warrior! - Me, too!
我是功夫侠士 ! 我也是 !
Come on. Come on!
加油，我可以的
Almost there.
快到了
What?
什么 ?
No! Oh, no!
不会吧 ! 不会吧 !
- Sorry, Po. - We'll bring you back a souvenir.
真可情，阿波 我们会攻你拿纪念品
No. I'll bring me back a souvenir.
不，我要自己去拿纪念品
It is an historic day.
今天是压史性的一刻
Isn't it, Master Oogway?
没错吧，厚大仙 ?
Yes, and one I feared I would not live to see.
没错 我逮担心我等不到这一天
Are your students ready?
你的徒弟准备好了吐 ?
Yes, Master Oogway.
好了，锡大仙
Know this, old friend.
老朋友，你得明白…
Whomever I choose will not only bring peace to the valley...
我挑的人… 不仅会为这壬带来平静
...but also to you.
也能为你带来平静
Let the tournament begin!
比武大赛开始 !
Yeah.
好耶，哈哈 !
No, no, wait!
不!不!不!等一下1!
I'm coming! Wait, wait!
我来了哟 ! 等一下 !
Hey! Open the door!
不 !列关门 !
Let me in!
让我进去 !
Citizens of the Valley of Peace,
和平谷的乡亲父老
it is my great honor to present to you... Tigress!
我很荣幸介绍…悍婚虎 !
Viper! Crane! Monkey! Mantis!
俏小龙 ! 才蕉 ! 猴王 ! 快星晴 !
The Furious Five!
盖世五侠!
Yeah, the Furious Five!
好耶，鞭世五侠!
Warriors, prepare!
各位，请准备好
Wait. No. Oh, peeky-hole.
等一下…有个洞可以偷看
- Ready for battle! - Yeah.
比武开始 !
The Thousand Tongues of Fire.
烽火连天曾
Look at that.
你看看
Hey! Get out of the way!
抽到我了哟
And finally Master Tigress!
最后是…悍婚虎 !
And believe me, citizens, you have not seen anything yet.
相信我 你们还没有见识到真功夫
know!
那还用说 !
Master Tigress! Face Iron Ox and his Blades of Death.
悍寻虎对抗千手绝命刀织霸牛 !
l sense the Dragon Warrior is among us.
我感觉到神龙大侠就在这壬
Citizens of the Valley of Peace,
和平谷的乡亲父老
Master Oogway will now choose the Dragon Warrior!
缆大仙现在将选出神龙大使 !
Oh, no! No, no, wait!
不!竺一下1
Po!
阿波
What are you doing?!
你在干 ?
What does it look like I'm doing?! Stop!
你说呢? 别放样 !
I'm going to see the Dragon Warrior!
我一定要看到神龙大侠 !
But I don't understand. You finally had the noodle dream!
我不懂，你好不容易欧到类人条 !
I lied. I don't dream about noodles, Dad.
我说议，我没葛到焰人条，老和区
I love kung fu!
我热爱功夫1!
Come on, son. Let's get back to work.
走吧，儿耶，回去干活儿吧
OK.
好吧
Come back!
回来 !
What's going on?
怎广回事 ?
Where...?
我在哪里 ?
What are you pointing...?
你干嘛指我 ?
OK. Sorry.
天啊，对不起
I just wanted to see who the Dragon Warrior was.
我只想看谁是神龙大侠
How interesting.
有意思
Master, are you pointing at me?
大仙，你在指我唉?
- Him. - Who?
他 谁?
- You. - Me?
你 我?
The universe has brought us the Dragon Warrior!
老天答把神龙大侠送来这里
- What? - What?!
什么 ?
Stop, wait! Who told you to...?
等等 1! 谁叫你们…
Master Oogway, wait.
范大仙…等一下
That flabby panda can't possibly be the answer to our problem.
那焦胖驴猎不可能是神龙大侠
You were about to point at Tigress and that thing fell in front of her!
你本来要指的是悍婚虎 结果那玩意从天而降
That was just an accident!
这只是个意外
There are no accidents.
世上汉有意外
Forgive us, Master. We have failed you.
对不起，师父 徒儿阐负了您的期望
No. If the panda has not quit by morning
不，如果那焦熊猎 明早前没落跑
then I will have failed you.
我才是辜负你们呢 !
Wait! Wait, wait, wait! I bring a message...
等一下…等一下… 我有口信要给典狼长
...from Master Shifu.
是功夫大师交代的
What?!
什么 ?
"Double the guard?!"
加倍守卫人数 ?
"Extra precautions?!"
要我们提高葡觉?
"Your prison may not be adequate?!"
这牢和可能不金坚固 ?
You doubt my prison security?!
你是在质疑我们的安全措施虽 ?
Absolutely not.
绝对不敢
Shifu does. I'm just the messenger.
是功夫大铺 我只负责送信
I'll give you a message for your Master Shifu.
者我带个话给你的功夫大绩
Escape from Chorh-Gom prison is impossible!
想从长距大牢逃走比登天还准
Impressive, isn't it?
了不起吧 ?
It's very impressive.
是啊，真的很了不起
One way in, one way out.
只有一个出入口
One thousand guards and one prisoner.
一千名守和本看守一名犯人
Yes, except that prisoner...
是的…不明犯人
.. is Tai Lung.
…是残鹏
Take us down.
放我们下去
What are you doing?
不要的
Oh, my.
老天答
Behold Tai Lung.
这就是残豹
I'm just gonna wait right here.
我在这和里等就行了
It's nothing to worry about. It's perfectly safe.
安听，别担心，这里绝对安全
Crossbows! At the ready!
十字己手 ! 待命 !
Hey, tough guy, did you hear?
喂 ! 硬汉 ! 你匠到我讲话吗 !
Oogway's giving someone the Dragon Scroll, and it's not gonna be you.
缆大仙终人於选出神龙大侠了 可异那个人不是你
Don't get him mad.
别惹他生气 !
What's he gonna do about it? I've got him completely immobilized.
他又能怎样 ? 他现在根本动不了
Did I step on the wittle kitty's tail?
我是不是踩到你的猫尾巴呀?
I'm good. I've seen enough.
我看金了
I'll tell Shifu he has nothing to worry about.
我会跟大师说他的担心是多余的
No, he doesn't.
他想太多了
I'll tell him that.
我一定会塌告他
Can we please go now?
可以走了吗 ?
Dragon Warrior! Dragon Warrior!
神龙大使 ! 神龙大侠…
Wait a second!
等一下
I think there's been a slight mistake. Everyone seems to think that I'm...
我想大概搞错了 大家好像以为我是…
The Sacred Hall of Warriors! No way!
味，英雄可殿 ! 超酷的
Look at this place.
这地方太炫了!
Master Flying Rhino's armor, with authentic battle damage!
飞天织犀侠的战甲 ! 上面玩有打癌留下来的裂痕
The Sword of Heroes!
忆鞭英雄刀 !
Said to be so sharp you can cut yourself just by looking.
据说它锋铝扰比 联一限就能消血
The Invisible Trident of Destiny!
迷魂隐形三又吉
I've only seen paintings of that painting.
我以前只看过这幅邵的海报
No!
哇塞…
The legendary Urn of Whispering Warriors.
幻语英才神襄
Said to contain the souls of the entire Tenshu Army.
据说装满所有孝勇军的英霆
Hello.
有人在吗?
Have you finished sight-seeing?
你参观完了没有?
Sorry, l should have come to you first.
歹热，我应该先来拜见你才半
My patience is wearing thin.
我快失去耐性了
Well, ! mean, it's not like you were going anywhere.
反正你待在计里又没别处可去
- Would you turn around? - Sure.
塌过来 好啊
How's it going?
嗨，怎广样 ?
How do you get 5,000... Master Shifu!
你怎广把五千个…功夫大师 !
Someone... broke that.
有人把它再破了
But I'll fix it. Do you have some...
我会把它蒜好 有没有…
.. glue?
三秒胁 ?
A splinter.
好痛，刺伤了
So you're the legendary Dragon Warrior?
你就是传说中的神龙大侠?
- l guess so. - Wrong!
大概是吧 ! 错 !
You are not the Dragon Warrior. You will never be the Dragon Warrior until...
你不是! 你也永踪不会成为神龙大侠
.. you have learned the secret of the Dragon Scroll.
除非你鲁成神龙秘笈里的神功
So, how does this work?
我要怎广拿呀 ?
Do you have a ladder, or a trampoline, or...?
有没有梯子，或是弹簧床 ?
You think it's that easy? That I'll just hand you the secret
你以为我会这广简音…
One must first master the highest level of kung fu.
你必须十八般武艺样样精通
And that is impossible if that one is someone like you.
看你这德性也知道这不可能
Someone like me?
我这德性 ?
Yes, look at you! This fat butt! Flabby arms!
没错，看看你 大屁股 ! 蝴蝶袖 !
Those are sensitive in the flabby parts.
咀，很痛耶
And this ridiculous belly.
还有圆滚渡的游泳力
And utter disregard for personal hygiene.
整个人更是朋到不行
Now, wait a minute. That's uncalled for.
等等，明人也留点情面吧
Don't stand that close. I can smell your breath.
别靠这广近，我并得到你的口短
Listen, Oogway said I was...
锡大仙说我是…
The Wuxi Finger Hold. Not the Wuxi Finger Hold!
扼锡碎骨指? ! 别用扰锡碎明指对付我 !
Oh, you know this hold?
你知道这一招 ?
Developed by Master Wuxi in the Third Dynasty.
扼锡大绩在第三朝时独创的绝招
Then you know what happens when I flex my pinky.
你一定知道 如果我小指一动的话…
- No, no! - You know the hardest part of this?
不要啦 ! 你知道这招最准的是什么吗 ?
The hardest part is cleaning up afterwards.
最困难的地方是之后的清理工作
OK, OK, take it easy.
好啦，我曝了，别乱来
Now listen closely, panda.
熊猫，给我观好
Oogway may have picked you, but when I'm through with you,
龟大仙也许选中你 不过等我把你折磨金了
I promise you, you're going to wish he hadn't! Are we clear?
你会希望这是一场欧 你瞳吗?
Good.
很好
I can't wait to get started.
我等不及要开始了
- Let's begin. - Wait, wait, wait.
开始练功吧 等一下
What?
什么 ?
- Now? - Yes, now.
现在? 对，现在
Unless the great Oogway was wrong and you are not the Dragon Warrior.
除非你承认葛大仙挑错人… 你不是神龙大侠
Oh, OK, well...
好吧
I don't know if l can do all of those moves.
不遇我不确定我会那些招数
Well, if we don't try, we'll never know, will we?
不试怎广知道呢
Yeah, it's just, maybe we can find something more suited to my level.
只是… 也许我们能从通合我的等级开始
What level is that?
那是哪一级呢?
Well, I'm not a master, but...
我没学过什么功夫
.. let's just start at zero. Level zero.
就从第零级开始吧
No. There is no such thing as level zero.
这里没有 有那种春蛋才第零级
- Maybe I can start with that. - That?
从那个玩意开始吧
We use that for training children and propping the door open when it's hot.
那是给小孩张习用的 选有天气热时用来撑开门的
But if you insist...
不通既然你坚持的话
The Furious Five!
味，黄世五侠 !
You're bigger than your action figures. Except, you, Mantis. You're the same.
你们比你们的公仔大多了 你例外，快屿时，你北乎一样小
Go ahead, panda. Show us what you can do.
开始吧，和熊猫，好好大展身手
Are they gonna watch, or should I wait till they get back to work?
他们要看吗 ?还是先等他们走?
Hit it.
打它
OK, yeah. I mean, I just ate. So I'm still digesting.
好吧，不过我才吃鲍，还没消化
So my kung fu might not be as good as... later on.
我的动作会比平常…避一点
Just hit it.
快出手吧
All right.
好哎
What you got? You got nothing, ‘cause I got it right here.
你有什么料? 你打不过我的啦
You picking on my friends? Get ready to feel thunder.
你在葡负我朋友鄙? 好脆唉走!
I'm coming at you with crazy feet.
色影对都出来了 你要怎广办 ?
Come on. I'm a blur. You've never seen bear style.
看不清楚我吧 你疙看过熊猫拳吧
You've only seen praying mantis.
你只看过我的时时搏
Or monkey style.
或者我应该用猴犀利那招
Orl could come at you snickety-snake.
或是用蛇形刁手来对付你
Would you hit it!
你到底要不要攻机 ?
All right. All right.
好哎，好听
Why don't you try again? A little harder.
再试一炊，打重一点
How's that?
这次不梵吧….
That hurts.
好痛哦
This will be easier than I thought.
要远走他真是易如反掌
I'm feeling a little nauseous!
我有点想吐耶
Those are hard!
这粉硬耶 !
My tenders.
我的蛋蛋…
How did I do?
我表现的怎样 ?
There is now a level zero.
你的确是货真价实的第零级
- There's no words. - No denying that.
我完全傻眼 真的
What was Master Oogway thinking?
我不懂息大仙的决定
The poor guy's gonna get himself killed.
这可情的僚伙必死撩疑
He is so mighty!
他还真“大焦”
The Dragon Warrior fell out of the sky on a ball of fire!
神龙大傅带著火球从天而降呢
When he walks, the very ground shakes!
他一走动还会引恬地震呢
One would think Master Oogway would choose someone who knew kung fu.
照理说更大人纠订该挑一个… 真正会功夫的人
Yeah, or could at least touch his toes.
对啊，至少手要碰得到脚趾头
Or even see his toes.
好歹也要看得到自己的脚下藉
OK.
小声点
Great.
真是的
Hi. You're up.
嗨…你醒啦 !
lam now.
被你吵醒的
Some day, huh?
今天真是太疯狂了
That kung fu stuff is hard work, right? Are your biceps sore?
功夫很难，对吧? 你的二头肌…会酸吗?
I've had a long and rather disappointing day, so...
我今天又累…又损足
Yeah, I should probably get to sleep now.
我该睡了
- Yeah, yeah, yeah. Of course. - OK, thanks.
没错，没错，当然 好吧，许了
It's just... Man, I'm such a big fan!
只是…我是你们的头费粉缘
You guys were amazing at the Battle of Weeping River.
你们在那场滑水炉之战 的表现好神
Outnumbered a thousand to one, but you didn't stop. You just...
以一拷千，毫不退
Sorry about that.
歹热，弄破了
Look, you don't belong here.
贡好，你不属藉这壬
I know. I know. You're right.
我蜡，我暗，你说的没错
I don't have... I just...
我啥都不会…
My whole life 1 dreamed of...
我一生的葛想…
No, I meant you don't belong here. I mean, in this room. This is my room.
不，你误会了 我说“你不属捡这壬”
Property of Crane.
震蕉的私人空间
OK. Right, right.
好，没错，汉错
So, you want to get to sleep.
对喔，你要睡觉了
- Yeah. - I'm keeping you up.
没错 我吵得你…不能睡
We got big things tomorrow.
我们明天还要绿功
All right. You're awesome. Last thing I'm gonna say. Bye-bye.
好吧，你有为亲，我告苹了 ! 好吧，猎铬
What was that?
你在叫我吧?
I didn't say anything.
我啥都没说
OK. All right. Good night.
好吧，晚安
Sleep well.
祝你香甜好葛
That seemed a little awkward.
有点堆座…
Master Tigress! I didn't mean to wake you.
悍寻虎，我不是故意吵醒人…
- You don't belong here. - Yeah, of course.
你不属於这壬 是啊，当然
This is your room.
这是你的乙间
I mean, you don't belong in the Jade Palace.
我是指你不属於玉和皇宫
You're a disgrace to kung fu, and if you have
你是武林的隘原
you will be gone by morning.
你最好明早郊并
Big fan!
欣赏你咀…
l see you have found the Sacred Peach Tree of Heavenly Wisdom.
看来你找到天机仙境的亿桃横了
Is that what this is? Sorry. ] thought it was just a regular peach tree.
是这棵帘唉 ? 歹执，我以为这是棵普通的桃山
I understand. You eat when you are upset.
我懂，你心烦就想大吃特吃
Upset? I'm not upset. What makes you think I'm upset.
心烦 ? 我没有啊 为…钨何你觉得我心烦 ?
So why are you so upset?
你究竟在烦什么 ?
I probably sucked more today than anyone in the history of kung fu.
我今天的表现大概是… 武林史上最避的吧
In the history of China. In the history of sucking!
选有中原史 可能还是避咖史上的第一避 !
Probably.
有可能
And the Five! Man, you should've seen them! They totally hate me.
至於盖世五侠… 你该看看他们的表情
Totally.
的确
How is Shifu ever going to turn me into the Dragon Warrior?
功夫大师如何能训急我… 成为神龙大侠?
l mean, I'm not like the Five.
我不像鞭世五侠…
I've got no claws, no wings, no venom.
我没有虎不 没有物收、没有蛇毒
Even Mantis has those... thingies.
就连快贬螂都有这样的…前脚
Maybe I should just quit and go back to making noodles.
或许我该放系，回去做类人条
Quit, don't quit.
放和奈、不放素
Noodles, don't noodles.
做类人条、不做类人条
You are too concerned with what was and what will be.
对於遇去与未来，你想太多了
There's a saying:
俗话说得好
Yesterday is history,
昨日是…通往云类
tomorrow is a mystery,
明日是…和这不可测
but today is a gift.
但今日…是上天赐予的礼物
That is why it is called the present.
所以才要把握当下
Fire crossbows!
发射十字己 !
Tai Lung is free! 1 must warn Shifu.
残豹越狱了 ! 我必须警告大师
- Not going anywhere! Neither is he! - Let go of me!
你哪里都去不成 ! 他也一样 放并我
Bring it up!
拉上来!
Wait! Bring it back!
等一下，放下来 !
- He's coming this way! - He won't get far. Archers!
他朝这里逃过来 ! 他逃不志，己稍手!
We're dead. So very, very dead.
我们死定了 ! 绝对逃不了 !
Not yet we're not. Now!
话可别说这广早…就是现在 !
- Can we run now? - Yes.
现在可以落跑了吗? 可以
I'm glad Shifu sent you.
我很高当大师派你来
l was beginning to think I'd been forgotten.
我以为他们把我给忘了呢
Fly back there and tell them...
秩回去告诉他们
. the real Dragon Warrior is coming home.
真的神龙大侠要回去了
Good morning, Master!
早安，大绩
Panda!
驴猫 !
Wake up!
给我起床 !
He's quit.
他放训了
What do we do now, with the panda gone? Who will be the Dragon Warrior?
大师，现在怎广办 ? 驴猫走了，谁当神龙大使呢 ?
All we can do is resume our training and trust that in time,
现在我们多续练功 相信不久之和合…
the true Dragon Warrior will be revealed.
真正的神龙大使就能确定了
What are you doing here?!
你在这壬干嘛 ?
Hi! Good morning, Master!
嗨，早安，大绩
I thought I'd warm up a little.
我想我最好暖身一下
You're stuck.
你卡住了
Stuck? Nah. What? Stuck?
卡住?才洛有，什么 ?
Nah. This is one of my... Yeah, I'm stuck.
不，我只是… 是啊，我卡住了
- Help him. - Oh, dear.
帮他 要命
Maybe on three. One, two...
数到三…一，二
.. three.
三 了
- Thank you. - Don't mention it.
感激不避 不必言谢
- No, really, l appreciate... - Ever.
不，真的，我很感谢… 别再提了1! 1!
You actually thought you could learn to do a full split in one night?
你真的以为能在一夜之间 就能学会一字马…
It takes years to develop one's flexibility!
这得花好北年 苦综身体的秒软度
And years longer to apply it in combat!
还要再花好北年才能与人遇招
Put that down!
给我放下
The only souvenirs we collect here are bloody knuckles and broken bones.
我们这和里只收集 血淋淋的关节以及碎掉的骨
Yeah! Excellent.
好极了1 11
Let's get started.
开始练功
- Are you ready? - was born re...
你准备好了吗 ? 我打娘胎时就淮…
I'm sorry, brother. I thought you said you were ready.
唉哟 !
That was awesome! Let's go again!
太角了 ! 再来一次 !
I've been taking it easy on you, panda. But no more.
我一直对你手下留情，驴和猫 但下不为例
Your next opponent will be me.
你下一个对手就是…我
All right! Yeah, let's go!
好啊，来比吧
Step forth.
靠近一点
The true path to victory is to find your opponent's weakness...
知己知人彼，百战百腾 找出对手的弱点
..and make him suffer for it.
让他痛不欲生
To take his strength and use it against him...
然合借力使力
...until he finally falls...
直到他倒地不起
..OF quits.
或是认输
A real warrior never quits.
但真正的大侠绝不会认输
Don't worry, Master. I will never quit!
鼻操心，大绩 我绝不放豪 !
If he's smart, he won't come back up those steps.
他要是取明就不会再息上来
But he will.
但是他会
He's not going to quit, is he?
他死也不放束，对吧 ?
He's not going to quit bouncing, I'll tell you that.
那他膛会负续掉下山去的 我保证
I thought you said acupuncture would make me feel better.
你说针灸能舒绥疫痛
Trust me, it will.
没距烟你，很有效
It's just not easy finding the right nerve points under all this...
只是你的究位粉难找…
- Fat? - Fur. was going to say fur.
肥肉 ? 我是说太多毛啦 !
Sure you were.
你人真好
Who am I to judge a warrior based on his size? Look at me.
武功的强弱不在身材的大小 看我就知道
I'm over here.
我在这冰啦
Maybe you should look at this again.
或许你该再看仔细点
Oh, OK.
好吧
Stop it. Stop!
干瘦?别关了，我不玩了
I know Master Shifu is trying to inspire me and all...
我知道功夫大鲁 一直斌著点化我
...but if I didn't know better, I'd say he was trying to get rid of me.
不盯解他的人… 还以为他想赶我走
I know he can seem kind of heartless...
我晓得他很冷酷乱情
...but he wasn't always like that.
但他不是一直这柑
According to legend,
据说…
there was once a time when Master Shifu actually used to smile.
师父曾经是…会笑的人
- No! - Yes.
是真的!
But that was before.
那是之前…
Before what?
什么之前…
Before Tai Lung.
在残鹏之前
We're not really supposed to talk about him.
我们不是不准谈残鹏的事吐 ?
Well, if he's going to stay here, he should know.
不，他要留下就得知道
Guys, guys, I know about Tai Lung.
我盯残鹏是何方神醒
He was a student. The first ever to master the thousand scrolls of kung fu.
他以前也是徒弟，他是万中之园 第一个钙会功夫秘招的人
And then he turned bad, and now he's in jail.
但他变束，现在被关在大宰和里
He wasn't just a student.
他不仅仅是徒弟…
Shifu found him as a cub...
师父在他年幼时收养他
..and he raised him as his son.
大师视他如已出
...Shifu trained him.
师父训鲁他
He believed in him. He told him he was destined for greatness.
对他寄予厚望 告诉他会成为伟大侠士
It was never enough for Tai Lung.
不过有残鹏的野心太大
He wanted the Dragon Scroll.
他想要得到神龙秘笈
But Oogway saw darkness in his heart and refused.
缆大仙看出他心卫不正，拒绝了
Outraged, Tai Lung laid waste to the valley.
他气急败壤，大病和平谷
He tried to take the scroll by force.
他企图强行硬取神龙秘笈
And Shifu had to destroy what he had created.
师父人必须毁了… 他一心坊培的爱徒
But how could he?
但他下不了手
Shifu loved Tai Lung like he had never loved anyone before.
残豹是师父的得意弟子
Or since.
他也最疼党他
And now he has a chance to make things right.
现在…他有机会句补通错
To train the true Dragon Warrior.
调教出真正的神龙大使
And he's stuck with you.
不遇他的期望各卡在…你身上
A big fat panda who treats it like a joke.
又大焦又肥胖的熊钳 把综武当成玩笑
That is it!
我受金了 !
Wait! My fault! l accidentally tweaked his facial nerve.
我的错! 我插到他的颜面神经究 !
And may have also stopped his heart.
他的心跳好像也停了
Inner peace.
平心静气
Would whoever is making that flapping sound quiet down?!
出怪声的信伙给我安静 !
Oh, Zeng.
原来是小张
Excellent.
来得正好
l could use some good news right now.
你是来通报好消息的吧
Master! Master!
大人了仙工大仙 !
I have... It's... It's very bad news.
我有…咽…很壤的消息
Shifu.
大旺
There is just news. There is no good or bad.
消息就是消息 没有所谓的好或壤
Master, your vision. Your vision was right.
大仙，你的预言成真了
Tai Lung has broken out of prison. He's on his way.
残豹逃狱了，他要打通来
That is bad news...
这真的是款消息…
.. if you do not believe that the Dragon Warrior can stop him.
…如果你不信和神龙大使能阻止他
The panda? Master, that panda is not the Dragon Warrior.
那焦熊猫 ? 大仙，他不是神龙大侠呼
He wasn't meant to be here! It was an accident.
他根本没那个料，那只是意外
There are no accidents.
世上汉有意外
Yes, I know. You've said that already.
我知道，你说遇两光了
- Twice. - Well, that was no accident, either.
那也不是意外
Thrice.
这是第三次
My old friend,
我的老友…
the panda will never fulfill his destiny, nor you yours,
…熊猫和你永速也不会达成使命
until you let go of the illusion of control.
除非你能抛开心中的成见
Illusion?
成见?
Yes. Look at this tree, Shifu.
没错，看看那棵树
cannot make it blossom when it suits me,
我不能逼它开花
nor make it bear fruit before its time.
也不能融它结果
But there are things we can control.
不过有些事我能掌控
l can control when the fruit will fall.
我能让果子提早掉下来
And I can control...
我也能决定…
..where to plant the seed.
…在哪里种横
That is no illusion, Master.
这不是成见，大仙
Yes.
没错
But no matter what you do
但是不管你怎广做
that seed will grow to be a peach tree.
那粒种子迁是会长成桃模
You may wish for an apple or an orange, but you will get a peach.
你也许想要它长出葛果或桶子 不明你只会吃到桃子
But a peach cannot defeat Tai Lung!
但是一颗桃子不能打败残豹
Maybe it can.
搞不好可以
If you are willing to guide it.
只要你顾意引导它
To nurture it.
栽培它
To believe in it.
相信它
But how? How?
我该怎广做 ?
I need your help, Master.
我需要你的帮忙
No, you just need to believe.
不，你只要有信心就行
Promise me, Shifu.
答应我，大印
Promise me you will believe.
答应我你要有信心
I will try.
我会努力
Good.
很好
My time has come.
我的时展到了
You must continue your journey without me.
你必须自己完成这项使命
What are you...? Wait!
你说什么… ?
Master!
大仙 !
You can't leave me!
你不能斑下我 !
You must believe.
你一定要有信心
Master!
大仙 !
Yeah, so I'm like, "Fine, you may be a wolf,
就算你是恶狼
you may be the scariest bandit in Haijin Province...
选是超级奥客
...but you're a lousy tipper.”
给起小弗钾超小气的
Really? So how did you get out of there alive?
你真的这广说 ? 那你怎广安然障身的
I mean, I didn't actually say that...
我没真的说出来啦
...but ] thought it...
只是在心里想想而已
If he could read my mind, he'd be, like, "What?"
他会读心术的话就惨了
- This is really good! - No, come on.
真是太美味了 !
Try my dad's Secret Ingredient Soup. He actually knows the secret ingredient.
那你该东我老爸的祖传秘方煲温 但那是他的祖传秘方
What do you mean? This is amazing!
少来，这超好吃的
- You're a really good cook. - l wish my mouth was bigger.
哇塞，你府艺真好 真希望我嘴巴大一点
Tigress, you've got to try this.
悍旺虎，非得嗜噶
It is said that the Dragon Warrior can survive for months
人家说神龙大使
I guess my body doesn't know it's the Dragon Warrior yet.
我想我的身届还没感觉到… 自己是神龙大侠吧
I'm gonna need a lot more than dew and universe juice.
我需要更多的食物 还有那“天地万物”…的混汗
- What? - Nothing... Master Shifu.
干骂? 没事，你好像师父
Never be the Dragon Warrior unless you lose 500 pounds and brush your teeth!
你绝对扰法成为神龙大侠
What is that noise you're making? Laughter? I never heard of it!
你在出什么怪声 ? 我从求没孤过
Work hard, panda, and maybe someday...
加油，驴猫，也许有一天…
.. you will have ears like mine.
你也会长出像我一样的耳采
That's good.
超像的
Ears. It's not working for you? I thought they were pretty good.
耳条 ! 你觉得不好笑吗? 我倒是觉得很好笑
It's Shifu!
师父 !
Of course it's Shifu. What do you think I'm doing?
这当然是师父 装得不像吗 ?
Master Shifu!
师父…
You think this is funny?
你把这当儿上?
Tai Lung has escaped and you're acting like children!
残豹逃山大牢了 你还在这壬胡病
- What? - He is coming for the Dragon Scroll,
啥米? 他要来拾走神龙秘艇
and you are the only one who can stop him.
而你是唯一能阻止他的人
And I was saying you got no sense of humor.
哈哈，我还说你没有幽鞭感
I'm gonna... stop Tai Lung.
要我去阻止…
What? You're serious? And I have to...?
你没说笑 ?我必须…
Master Oogway will stop him, like he did before.
…范大仙会阻正他 他以前阻正遇，现在也行
Oogway cannot!
他不行
Not anymore.
再也不行了
Our only hope is the Dragon Warrior.
我们唯一的希望就是… 神龙大使
- The panda? - Yes, the panda!
驴和猎 ? 没错，就是熊猫
Master, let us stop Tai Lung. This is what you've trained us for.
大师，让我们阻止残豹 这就是你训急我们的目的啊
No! It is not your destiny to defeat Tai Lung.
不，打败残鹏不是你们的使命
It is his!
是他的
Where'd he go?
他人呢 ?
You cannot leave! A real warrior never quits.
你不能落跑 真正的侠士缀不放束
Watch me.
刘啊等
Come on.
提名忙
How am I supposed to beat Tai Lung? I can't even beat you to the stairs.
我怎广可能打败残豹 我连障梯都吃不消
You will beat him because you are the Dragon Warrior.
你会打败他… 为你是神龙大使
You don't believe that. You never believed that.
连你也不相信 你从来就不相信
From the beginning, you've tried to get rid of me.
从我来这壬，你就一直想直我走
Yes! was.
对，我当初是这样
But now I ask you to trust in your master as I have come to trust in mine.
不过现在我要你相信你的师父 就像我自己也开始相信
You're not my master. And I'm not the Dragon Warrior.
你才不是我的师父 我也不是神龙大侠
Then why didn't you quit?! You knew l wanted you gone, yet you stayed.
那你干嘛不放雍 ?
Yeah, I stayed.
没错，我没走…
I stayed because every time you threw a brick at my head
我没走，因为… 每炎你教训我、侮历我…
or said ! smelled, it hurt, but it could never hurt more
那的确伤了我的心 但更让人伤心的是
than it did every day of my life just being me.
每天汉潭焉重混日子
I stayed because ! thought, if anyone could change me...
我没走，因为… 我以为如果有人可以改变我
..could make me... not me...
能让我… 变得不像自己
. it was you.
那个人就是你
The greatest kung fu teacher in all of China!
全中国最伟大的功夫大印
But I can change you!
我可以改变你
I can turn you into the Dragon Warrior! And I will!
我可以让你变成神龙大侠 我现在做得到
Come on. Tai Lung is on his way here right now.
少来，残鹏就要求了 !
Even if it takes him a hundred years to get here, how are you...
就算他花一百年才跑到这填 你要怎广做…
...gonna change this into the Dragon Warrior?
才能让我这大洗时成为… 神龙大侠?
How?
你说啊怎次做 ?
- How?! - l don't know!
怎广做啊 ? 我不知道 !
I don't know.
我真的不知道
That's what I thought.
跟我想的一样
This is what you trained me for.
这就是我们绿武的目的
Tigress!
悍婚虎
Don't try and stop me.
列想阻止我
We're not trying to stop you.
我们不是想阻止你
We're coming with you!
我们要跟你站局作战
What? I eat when I'm upset, OK?
干骂? 我心烦就会狂吃，盯没 ?
No need to explain.
你不必解释《
I thought you might be Monkey. He hides his almond cookies on the top shelf.
我以为你是猴于 他都把查仁饼放在最上面
Don't tell Monkey.
别向猴王告状
- Look at you. - Yeah, I know, I disgust you.
看看你 我知道，你觉得我很吐
No, I mean, how did you get up there?
不，我在想你是怎广上去的 ?
I don't know. I guess that...
不晓得耶，我猜…
I don't know. I was getting a cookie.
我只是想吃饼乾吧
Yet you are ten feet off the ground.
但是你名一跳就跳到那广高
And you have done a perfect spilt.
而且还会标准的一字马
No, this? This is just...
这样吗 ?
.an accident.
一个意外
There are no accidents.
世上汉有意外
Come with me.
跟我来
I know you're trying to be all mystical and kung fuey...
我知道你要教我神奇的功夫
...but could you at least tell me where we're going?
不明至少告诉我还要多踪叫
You dragged me...
你大老速…
.all the way out here...
把我拖来这和里
..for a bath?
就是要我洗澡 ?
...we do not wash our pits in the Pool of Sacred Tears.
我们不会在村演池洗用肢窗的…
The Pool of...
什么池 ?
This is where Oogway unraveled the mysteries...
是更大仙调气和修行的圣地
This is the birthplace...
这壬是功夫的起源地
Do you want to learn kung fu?
你真想学功夫吗 ?
Yeah!
是的
Then l am your master!
那我就是你的师父
OK!
太感人了
Don't cry.
不要器
OK.
好的
When you focus on kung fu,
当你只想著要学武功…
. you stink.
…你很膛了
Perhaps that is my fault.
不也许这是我的错
I cannot train you the way I have trained the Five.
我不能用传统的方法教你
l now see that the way to get through to you...
唯一的方法是借由食物来点化你
Oh, great, ‘cause l am hungry.
棒采了，我印奖了
Good.
很好
When you have been trained, you may eat.
等你鳞完功才能吃东西
Let us begin.
开始练功吧
After you, panda.
你先吃，驴入
Just like that?
就这广简章 ?
No sit-ups? No ten-mile hike?
不做人饰取起坐?不跑山路 ?
Il vowed to train you, and you have been trained. You are free to eat.
我发专会训张你，我也做明了… 你可以吃包子
Enjoy.
请慢用
I said you are free to eat. Have a dumpling.
我说你可以吃包子，吃呀
You are free to eat.
你可以吃包子
- Am I?! - Are you?!
才怪 你行吐?
I'm not hungry.
我不能了
Master.
师父
Cut it!
把吊实下断
Where's the Dragon Warrior?
神龙大使在哪里 ?
How do you know you're not looking at her?
你怎廊知道不是我 ?
You think I'm a fool?
你把我当和白闻吗 ?
I know you're not the Dragon Warrior. None of you!
我知道你不是神衣大侠 你们都不是 !
heard how he fell out of the sky in a ball of fire.
聘说他带著火球从天而降
That he's a warrior unlike anything the world has ever seen.
他是世上节伟大的功夫高手
- Po? - So that is his name. Po.
阿波 ? 原来他叫阿波
Finally, a worthy opponent.
我终於遇见可数的对手了
Our battle will be legendary!
我们的生死决战将成为传奇
We've got this. Help her.
我们抓紧了，快去如她
Monkey!
猴王!
Gol
快去呀 !
What was I thinking?!
我这是自找苦吃叫
Mantis!
快星螂 !
Now!
出招 !
Shifu taught you well.
大师把你们教得很好
But he didn't teach you everything.
不明他留了一手没教你们
You have done well, panda.
你表现得很好，驴猫
Done well? Done well?
表现得很好? 只是很好?
I've done awesome!
我超般的!
The mark of a true hero is humility.
真正的英雄 应该具备谦庶的美德
But, yes, you have done...
没错，你超贡的
Guys? Guys?! They're dead!
大彩儿 ! 他们吗忆了
No, they're breathing. They're asleep? But their eyes are open.
不，还有呼吸 睡著了 ? 但眼睛是上肥开的
We were no match for his nerve attach.
我们甫不过他的点究攻过
He's gotten stronger.
他的武功又变强了
Who? Tai Lung? Stronger?
残豹?人变强了?
He's too fast!
他速度太快了
Sorry, Po.
歹款，阿波
I thought we could stop him.
我们以为能阻止他
He could have killed you.
他可以干掉你们
Why didn't he?
但他没有
So you could come back and strike fear into our hearts. But it won't work.
为你们的下场可以起嘛阻作用 不过他心机和白划了
It might. 1 mean, a little.
但他有叶到我 至少一点…
I'm pretty scared.
我者怕极了
You can defeat him, panda!
你可以打败他，和熊猫
Are you kidding? If they can't?!
你在说笑哮?
But you will have the one thing that no one else does.
但你所有一个绝拓仅有的东西…
You really believe I'm ready?
你真的以为我准备好了吗 ?
You are...
你准备好了
Behold the Dragon Scroll.
看仔细，神龙秘笈
It is yours.
它是你的了
Wait. What happens when I read it?
等一下，我读了会怎样 ?
Legend says you will be able to hear a butterfly's wing beat.
扰人知腊，根所传说… 你能匠见蝴蝶屎拇的微融
Really? That's cool.
真的? 好酷
Yes. And see light in the deepest cave.
没错 还能看见历丈深漳的微光
You will feel the universe in motion around you.
字宙万物的动静 你都会有所感应
Can I punch through walls?
我能单拳穿糙…
- Do a quadruple back flip? - Focus.
以及丧篇走壁吗 ? 事心
- Will L...?
可以隐形嘛?
- Oh, yeah, yeah.
好
Read it, Po, and fulfill your destiny.
然后达成你的使命
It's impossible to open.
超准并的
OK. Come on, baby. Come on now.
好紧吗…
Thank you.
谢了
I probably loosened it up for you though.
我刚刚已经耕并它了
OK, here goes.
好，我要看了
- It's blank. - What?!
是空白的 什么 ?
- Here, look. - No, lam forbidden to look upon...
你自己看 我不能看…
Blank. I don't...
不，怎广可能
I don't understand.
我不盯解
OK. So, like...
我知道了
.. Oogway was just a crazy old turtle after all.
钨大仙可能老人疯呆了
No. Oogway was wiser than us all.
不，大仙的智慧天人能及
Oh, come on! Face it, he picked me by accident.
少来，面对事实吧 他是意外挑中我的
Of course I'm not the Dragon Warrior. Who am I kidding?
我才不是神龙大使… 我在骗谁啊
But who will stop Tai Lung?
那谁能打败残豹呢?
He'll destroy everything and everyone.
他么恶不做，赶部负经
No.
不
Evacuate the valley. You must protect the villagers from Tai Lung's rage.
为了和平谷的安危 你们必须保护村民不受残豹感鲁
- What about you, Master? - l will fight him.
那您呢 ? 我会跟他对决
- What? - lcan hold him off long enough
啥米? 我可以抵拷他狗久…
for everyone to escape.
让大家求得及逃走
But, Shifu, he'll kill you.
可是师父…他会条死你
Then I will finally have paid for my mistake.
人这样我也能经补通错了
Listen to me, all of you.
徒儿们，匠好…
It is time for you to continue your journey without me.
现在开始你们要自立自强了
lam very proud to have been your master.
能当你们的师父，我感到很刁人秽
We've got to get them out safely.
我们必须确保大家安全离开
Come, little one. Let's find your mama.
小弟弟，我们一起去找妈咪
Viper, gather the southern farmers. Mantis, the north.
俏小龙，集合南尊的农民 快时师，北亲
Crane, light the way.
震宁，引壮大家
Look, it's the Dragon Warrior.
看，是神龙大侠
Hey, Dad.
嗨，老区
Po!
阿波 !
Good to have you back, son.
很高惧你回来了，儿子
Good to be back.
我也很高要回来…
Let's go, Po.
我们走吧，阿波
So for our next shop, it's time to face it...
我们的下一家店 我想要推出…
...the future of noodles is dice-cut vegetables...
蔬菜什锦类
...no longer slices.
蔬菜不切成狂
Also, I was thinking, maybe this time
我还打算…
You like that?
你开心吐?
Po, I'm sorry if things didn't work out.
阿波，我很遗幅 你没能如顾…
It just wasn't meant to be.
或许这就是你的命
Po, forget everything else.
阿波，列胡思乱想了
Your destiny still awaits.
你注定成为…
We are noodle folk. Broth runs deep through our veins.
类条世家的传人 就回血液里都流著类混
I don't know, Dad.
我不确定，老和区
Honestly, sometimes I can't believe I'm actually your son.
说实话，我有时很怀疑… 我真的是你的儿子吗?
Po...
阿波
...[ think it's time I told you something ! should have told you...
我想时候到了…. 我要告诉你一些…
...a long time ago.
你早该知道的事
OK.
好吧
The secret ingredient of my Secret Ingredient Soup.
我的祖传秘方煲混的祖传秘方…
Come here. The secret ingredient is...
祖传秘方是…
.. nothing.
什么都不加
You heard me. Nothing!
啥米? 你匠到了，什么都不加
There is no secret ingredient!
根本没有所谓的祖传秘方
Wait, wait. It's just plain old noodle soup?
等等，只是清汤业 ?
You don't add some kind of special sauce or something?
你没有加任何佐料跑 ?
Don't have to. To make something special, you just believe it's special.
不需要，想要东西与容不同 你必须相信它是与办不同的
There is no secret ingredient.
根本没有所谓的祖传秘方
l have come home, Master.
我回家了，绩父
This is no longer your home. And 1am no longer your master.
这不是你家，我也不是你师父
Oh, yes. You have a new favorite.
对哦，你收了个新党徒
So where is this Po?
你的高徒阿波在哪里?
Did I scare him off?
我把他嘛跑了吐?
This battle is between you and me.
这是你和我的决站
So, that is how it's going to be.
原来如此
That is how it must be.
没错，就是这样
I rotted in jail for 20 years because of your weakness!
你心太软，害我岁了20年苦守
Obeying your master is not weakness!
尊师重道缀不是软弱的表现
You knew I was the Dragon Warrior.
你明知道我就是神龙大侠
You always knew.
你一直都知道
But when Oogway said otherwise, what did you do?
但高竭说不是时，你做了什么 ?
What did you do?!
你有替我说话吗 ?
Nothing!
没有 !
You were not meant to be the Dragon Warrior! That was not my fault!
你不是神龙大侠，那不是我的错
Not your fault?!
不是你的错?
Who filled my head with dreams?!
是谁让我满胶子都是梦想 ?
Who drove me to train until my bones cracked?!
是谁逼我张功缚到断筋碎骨? ?
Who denied me my destiny?!
是谁害我当不成神龙大侠?
It was never my decision to make!
我从来都没有权力决定
It is now.
现在你有权力决定了
Give me the scroll!
把神龙秘笈给我 !
I would rather die.
我宣死也不给
All l ever did, I did to make you proud!
我缚功是为了…让你…以我为党
Tell me how proud you are, Shifu!
大师，告诉我你以我各可
Tell me!
告诉我 !
I have... l have always been proud of you.
我一直都以你为村
From the first moment, I've been...
从一开始…我就是
And it was my pride...
但就是这一点
..that blinded me.
也让我看不清真相
I loved you too much to see what you were becoming...
我太汐爱你了 看不出你的瑟变…
.. What I...
…我把你
...was turning you into.
完成一个大壕蛋
I'm...
我很抱娄
I don't want your apology.
我不要你道歉
l want my scroll!
我要神龙秘笈
What?!
什么 ?
Where is it?!
秘笈在哪里?
Dragon Warrior has taken the scroll halfway across China by now.
秘笈时就被神龙大使带走了 你永下得不到神龙秘笈
You will never see that scroll, Tai Lung.
你永速…都得不到
Stairs.
有疏楼梯累鉴了
Who are you?
你是谁?
Buddy, I am the Dragon Warrior.
老兄，我是神龙大使
You?
你 ? 哈哈…
Him? He's a panda.
他?了他是一焦驴和猫耶
You're a panda. What are you gonna do, big guy? Sit on me?
你能怎浪，大焦伴 ? 坐在我身上吗?
Don't tempt me.
别惹毛我
No. I'm gonna use this.
我手上有…这个
You want it? Come and get it.
想要吗 ?来拿啊
Finally!
终藉等到这一刻
That scroll is mine!
秘笈是我的 !
The scroll has given him power!
他绿成乱极神功
No!
不!
The power of the Dragon Scroll is mine!
神龙秘笈的力量… 属尖我的
It's nothing!
件秆都没写 !
It's OK. I didn't get it the first time, either.
别准遇，我蜀拿到时也不盯 !
What?
什么 ?
There is no secret ingredient.
没有所谓的秘笈
It's just you.
关键存乎於一心
Stop it!
不，列天了
I'm gonna pee.
我快尿出来…
You...
你…
..can't defeat me.
打不赢我的
I'm not a big fat panda.
我不是普通的胖能和猫…
I'm the big fat panda.
我万独一德二大胖的驴腻
The Wuxi Finger Hold!
执锡碎骨指 !
Oh, you know this hold?
你腊得这一招?
You're bluffing. You're bluffing. Shifu didn't teach you that.
少来，你在距我 师父不可能教你
Nope.
他是没教我
I figured it out. Skadoosh.
我乱师自通的，看招 !
The Dragon Warrior.
味，是神龙大侠 !
That's my boy! That big lovely kung fu warrior is my son!
那是我的孩子
Thanks, Dad.
谢了，老区
Hey, guys.
大彩儿
Master.
大旺
Master Shifu!
师父 !
Master!
大绩 !
Po.
阿波
You're alive.
你没指掉 ?
Or we're both dead.
还是我们都吗屁了
No, Master, I didn't die. defeated Tai Lung.
不，大师，我没死 我打败残鹏了
You did?
真的?
Wow. It is as Oogway foretold.
缆大仙说的没错
You are the Dragon Warrior.
你是神龙大使
You have brought peace...
你为这壬带来了平静
.and to me.
带来平静
Thank you.
谢谢
Thank you, Po.
谢谢，阿波
Thank you. Thank you.
谢谢，谢谢
No! Master! No, no, no, don't die, Shifu, please!
不，大师，不…别死 ! 师父，你别死 !
I'm not dying, you idiot!
我没死响，你这策蛋 !
Dragon Warrior...
我指神龙大侠…
.. Lam simply at peace. Finally.
我只是…心平静了 狗算能静心了
So, I should stop talking?
所以…我该并嘲吗 ?
If you can.
最好
Want to get something to eat?
要去吃些东西鄙?
Yeah.
好吧